ILGWU. Association contracts, 5780/191
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Association contracts
1916-1994
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/191
10.5 cubic feet
10.5 linear feet
Contracts
This collection consists of 800 agreements and contracts between the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union and associations of garment manufacturers.
7017193
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
July 2011
EAD encoding:
Cheryl Beredo, July 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of 800 agreements and contracts between the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union and associations of garment manufacturers.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU records
5780/075. ILGWU. Collective Bargaining Agreements
5780/075 mf. ILGWU. Collective Bargaining Agreements. Microfilm
5780/085. ILGWU. National War Labor Board case files
5780/145. ILGWU. Association Agreements. Out-of-Business Contracts
5780/146. ILGWU. Master Agreements. Out-of-Business Contracts
5780/147. ILGWU. Independents. Out-of-Business Contracts
5780/158. ILGWU. Out-of-Business Contracts
5780/202. ILGWU. Operations Department. Collective Bargaining Agreements
General
"Permanent deposit"
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by name of association.
Collective labor agreements; Clothing workers -- Labor unions; Textile workers -- Labor unions
7017193
- Affiliated Dress MFG New York City (folder 1 of 2), 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Affiliated Dress MFG New York City (folder 2 of 2), 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Affiliated Dress MFG New York City (folder 1 of 3), 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Affiliated Dress MFG New York City (folder 2 of 3), 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Affiliated Dress MFG New York City (folder 3 of 3), 1970-1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Allied Underwear New York City (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Allied Underwear, et al (office), 1963-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- American Cloak and Suit Manufacturers' Association, 1970- (Box 1, Folder 8)
- American Cloak Association (folder 1 of 3), 1951- (Box 1, Folder 9)
- American Cloak Association (folder 2 of 3), 1951- (Box 1, Folder 10)
- American Cloak Association (folder 3 of 3), 1951- (Box 1, Folder 11)
- American Cloak and Suit Manufacturers' Association (folder 1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- American Cloak and Suit Manufacturers' Association (folder 2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Apparel Men's Association New York City (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Apparel Manufacturers' Association of Puerto Rico, Inc. (folder 1 of 2), 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Apparel Manufacturers' Association of Puerto Rico, Inc. (folder 2 of 2), 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Associated Corset and Brassiere Manufacturers New York City (folder 1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Associated Corset and Brassiere Manufacturers New York City (folder 2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Associated Corset and Brassiere Manufacturers New York City (folder 3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Associated Corset and Brassiere Manufacturers NY out-of-town (folder 1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Associated Corset and Brassiere Manufacturers NY out-of-town (folder 2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Associated Dress Carriers of Brooklyn and Queens, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Associated Robe Manufacturers, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Association of Knitted Fabric Manufacturers, New York City (folder 1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Association of Knitted Fabric Manufacturers, New York City (folder 2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Association of Rain Apparel Contractors, New York City (folder 1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Association of Rain Apparel Contractors, New York City (folder 2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Atlantic Apparel Contractors (PA) (folder 1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Atlantic Apparel Contractors (PA) (folder 2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Belt Association New York City (folder 1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Belt Association New York City (folder 2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Belt Association New York City (folder 3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Children's Dress, Cotton Dress, and Sportswear Contractors Association (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Cloak and Suit Trucking Association, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Cotton Apparel and Robe Producers' Association of US (folder 1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Cotton Apparel and Robe Producers' Association of US (folder 2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Fashion Apparel Manufacturers' Association (folder 1 of 2), 1966- (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Fashion Apparel Manufacturers' Association (folder 2 of 2), 1966- (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Fashion Apparel Manufacturers' Association (Philadelphia) (folder 1 of 3), 1946-1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Fashion Apparel Manufacturers' Association (Philadelphia) (folder 2 of 3), 1946-1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Fashion Apparel Manufacturers' Association (Philadelphia) (folder 3 of 3), 1946-1966 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Garment Truckmen Association of NJ (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Greater Blouse, Skirt and Undergarment Association, Inc. (Blouse Division) (folder 1 of 2), 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Greater Blouse, Skirt and Undergarment Association, Inc. (Blouse Division) (folder 2 of 2), 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Greater Blouse, Skirt and Undergarment Contractors (Sportswear Division) (folder 1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Greater Blouse, Skirt and Undergarment Contractors (Sportswear Division) (folder 2 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Greater Blouse, Skirt and Undergarment Contractors (Sportswear Division) (folder 3 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Greater Blouse…Undergarment Contractors (folder 1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Greater Blouse…Undergarment Contractors (folder 2 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Greater Blouse…Undergarment Contractors (folder 3 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Industrial Association of House Dress, Robe and Uniform Manufacturers, Inc., 1946-1963 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Industrial Association of Juvenile Apparel Manufacturers, Inc. (folder 1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Industrial Association of Juvenile Apparel Manufacturers, Inc. (folder 2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers, Inc. (folder 1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers, Inc. (folder 2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Infants' and Children's Coat Association and Cloak Joint Board (folder 1 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Infants' and Children's Coat Association and Cloak Joint Board (folder 2 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Infants' and Children's Coat Association and Cloak Joint Board (folder 3 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Infants', Children's and Girls' Sportswear and Coat Association (folder 1 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Infants', Children's and Girls' Sportswear and Coat Association (folder 2 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Infants', Children's and Girls' Sportswear and Coat Association (folder 3 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Infants' and Children's Novelties Association, New York City (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Intimate Apparel Association, New York City, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Knitted Accessories Group, New York City (folder 1 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Knitted Accessories Group, New York City (folder 2 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Knitted Accessories Group, New York City (folder 3 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Knitted Accessories Group, New York City (folder 4 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Metropolitan Knitted Textile Association of NY, 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Knitted Outerwear Manufacturers Association (Philadelphia) (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Lingerie Manufacturers Association, New York City, 1933-1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Ladies' Apparel Contractors Association and United Better Dress Manufacturers Association, 1979-1994 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Master Truckmen of America (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Merchants Association (folder 1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Merchants Association (folder 2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Montreal Dress and Sportswear Manufacturers Guild (folder 1 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Montreal Dress and Sportswear Manufacturers Guild (folder 2 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Montreal Dress and Sportswear Manufacturers Guild (folder 3 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 8)
- National Association of Blouse Manufacturers, New York City (folder 1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 9)
- National Association of Blouse Manufacturers, New York City (folder 2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 10)
- National Dress Manufacturers, New York City (folder 1 of 2), 1933-1970 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- National Dress Manufacturers, New York City (folder 2 of 2), 1933-1970 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- National Skirt and Sportswear, New York City (folder 1 of 2), 1933-1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- National Skirt and Sportswear, New York City (folder 2 of 2), 1933-1984 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Negligee Manufacturers Association of NY (folder 1 of 2), 1933-1984 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Negligee Manufacturers Association of NY (folder 2 of 2), 1933-1984 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- New England Manufacturers Association (Fall River, MA) (folder 1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 5)
- New England Manufacturers Association (Fall River, MA) (folder 2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 6)
- New England Sportswear (Boston) (folder 1 of 2), 1979-1991 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- New England Sportswear (Boston) (folder 2 of 2), 1979-1991 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- New England Sportswear (Boston) (folder 1 of 2), 1941-1979 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- New England Sportswear (Boston) (folder 2 of 2), 1941-1979 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- New York Coat and Suit Association (folder 1 of 2), 1964- (Box 7, Folder 11)
- New York Coat and Suit Association (folder 2 of 2), 1964- (Box 7, Folder 12)
- New Jersey Apparel Contractors Association (folder 1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 1)
- New Jersey Apparel Contractors Association (folder 2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 2)
- New York Coat and Suit Association (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Infants' and Children's Coat Association, Local 30 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- New York Raincoat Manufacturers (folder 1 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 5)
- New York Raincoat Manufacturers (folder 2 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 6)
- New York Raincoat Manufacturers (folder 3 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 7)
- New York Skirt and Sportswear Association (folder 1 of 2), 1979-1994 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- New York Skirt and Sportswear Association (folder 2 of 2), 1979-1994 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- New York Skirt and Sportswear Shipping (Local 102) (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Northeast Apparel Association (PA) (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Passementerie and Trimming Manufacturers Association, New York City (folder 1 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Passementerie and Trimming Manufacturers Association, New York City (folder 2 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Passementerie and Trimming Manufacturers Association, New York City (folder 3 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Philadelphia Waist and Dress Manufacturers Association, 1916-1946 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Plastic and Metal Products Manufacturers Association New York City (folder 1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Plastic and Metal Products Manufacturers Association New York City (folder 2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Plastic Soft Materials Association, New York City (folder 1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Plastic Soft Materials Association, New York City (folder 2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Pleaters, Stitchers and Embroiders Association, Inc. (folder 1 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Pleaters, Stitchers and Embroiders Association, Inc. (folder 2 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Pleaters, Stitchers and Embroiders Association, Inc. (folder 3 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Popular Priced Dress Manufacturers Group (folder 1 of 2), 1933-1970 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Popular Priced Dress Manufacturers Group (folder 2 of 2), 1933-1970 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Puerto Rican Corset and Brassiere Association (folder 1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Puerto Rican Corset and Brassiere Association (folder 2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Quebec Fashion Apparel Manufacturers Guild (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Sportswear Apparel Association, Inc. (folder 1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Sportswear Apparel Association, Inc. (folder 2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Toronto Cloak Manufacturers Association (folder 1 of 2), 1941-1991 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Toronto Cloak Manufacturers Association (folder 2 of 2), 1941-1991 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Theatrical Costumes, New York City (folder 1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Theatrical Costumes, New York City (folder 2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Toronto Dress and Sportswear Manufacturers Guild (folder 1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Toronto Dress and Sportswear Manufacturers Guild (folder 2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Undergarment Accessories Association (folder 1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Undergarment Accessories Association (folder 2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 8)
- United Dress Manufacturers Association (folder 1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 9)
- United Dress Manufacturers Association (folder 2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 10)
- United Popular Dress Manufacturers Association (Box 10, Folder 11)
- United Knitwear Manufacturers League (folder 1 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 12)
- United Knitwear Manufacturers League (folder 2 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 13)
- United Knitwear Manufacturers League (folder 3 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 1)
- United Knitwear Manufacturers League, Inc. (Shipping) Local 99 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- United Better Dress Manufacturers' Association, Inc. (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Women's Apparel Chains Association (Box 11, Folder 4)